[Music]
Hi everyone. In this tutorial, I'm going
to show you how to get started with
Blitzet. Blitzet helps you plan your day
and week by breaking down your work into
manageable tasks using smart timers and
focus modes and many other cool features
that are all built to help you achieve
an invarian flow state. So, as we say,
you can win your day every day. To get
started, you'll need a Mac or Windows
computer. Blitz works on Mac OS 12.3 or
later, supporting both Intel and Apple
Silicon processors, as well as Windows
10 and Windows 11. Mobile apps for iOS
and Android are coming soon, so you'll
be able to stay productive on the go.
Setting up your account is super easy,
but first you need to download the app.
Head over to Blitz.app and go to the
download section. There, choose your
operating system, Mac OS, Intel, Apple
Silicon, or Windows.
Once you install and open the app,
you'll be asked to enter the email you
want to use with
Blitzet. Then you'll need to agree to
the privacy and data collection terms.
And yeah, be sure to go ahead and give
it a quick read or simply pretend you
did. After that, Blitzet will send you a
confirmation code to your email. Just
enter that code in the app and you are
signed up.
The last step is to enter your first and
last name and then you are all set to
start crushing your
tasks. Here's a quick look at the Blitz
interface. This is your home section
where you can create and manage lists.
They help you organize different
projects or areas of your work. Let's
create the first list. Choose a name and
icon for it and press create. You can
edit your list anytime by clicking the
three dot button and pressing
edit. Now let's open it. Okay. So inside
the list you can see the columns which
help you organize your tasks based on
priority. Here we have columns titled
today, this week and backlog. This one
is for tasks scheduled beyond one week.
Blitz lets you switch between all lists
view which shows all of your tasks and
single list view focusing on one project
at a time. To add a task, click the add
task button. Type your task and hit
enter or confirm button. You can edit
tasks anytime. Add notes, subtasks, or
estimated time to plan timelines for
task completion. Check out other
tutorials or help center for more
details about these
tools. One of Blitz's core features is
Blitz mode, a focused work mode designed
to keep distractions away. Hit Blitz it
now button when you have the tasks
added. Your top task will automatically
go into lifetime with the rest of your
tasks organized in a clean list below.
Here you can see everything you have
planned for the day. Organize your tasks
and add the new ones and view the tasks
you completed during the day session.
You can also switch between the
lists to switch the panel into a little
floating focus timer that is always
visible on the screen. You can either
click the top right arrow icon or click
the focus mode button at the bottom. Now
you can work on your tasks having the
timer always visible. You can always
take a break, pause or skip the task,
add a note or once you are done, mark it
as
done.
Yes, and it's just a brief overview.
Blitz offers you lots of other features
like sheduling, anti-distraction alerts,
integrations, customizations, and other
helpful tools. We'll talk about them in
our next tutorials. Blitz offers
different pricing plans to fit your
needs. You get a 7-day free trial to
explore all features, and you can choose
a plan anytime during or after your
trial period. There is a monthly plan
for
$4.99, or you can buy a lifetime access
to Blitzet for $97. You pay once and use
Blitz forever. Well, let's pretend there
is anything that lasts forever. I hope
now you have a general picture of what
Blitzet is and how to get start with it.
Be sure to check other videos on our
YouTube channel and join our Discord
community.